'At the time the murder was committed, I was travelling on the 8 o'clock train to London,' said the man.
'Do you always catch such an early train?'
asked the inspector.
'Of course I do,' answered the man.
'I must be at work at 10 o'clock.
My employer will confirm that I was there on time.'
'Would a later train get you to work on time?'
asked the inspector.
'I suppose it would, but I never catch a later train.'
'At what time did you arrive at the station?'
'At ten to eight.
I bought a paper and waited for the train.'
'And you didn't notice anything unusual?'
'Of course not.'
'I suggest,' said the inspector, 'that you are not telling the truth.
I suggest that you did not catch the 8 o'clock train, but that you caught the 8.25 which would still get you to work on time.
You see, on the morning of the murder, the 8 o'clock train did not run at all.
It broke down at Ferngreen station and was taken off the line.'